

MICHAIL KARNAS

+⁺+ +++

Senior Analytics Manager @ Tesco PLC

RESUME

Following the completion of my MEng in Civil Engineering and MSc in Operations and logistics Management, I joined Tesco as an Insight Analyst in October 2015. Since then I have enjoyed a rapid increase in responsibility, gaining two promotions during a very challenging period for the Business. My success was mainly founded on delivering numerous high profile Tableau dashboards, providing training and consultation as well as delivering the first International dashboard integrating the Teradata and Hadoop ecosystems.

EXPERIENCE

Senior Analytics Manager – International Reporting, Web Apps & Visualizations @ Tesco PLC

2020 - Current

- Leading a team of analysts to tackle some of the most complex data challenges such as big data platform integration between Teradata, SQL Server and Hadoop Ecosystems.
- Develop and consult on advanced visualisation solutions aiming for the perfect balance between performance and level of detail that satisfies user needs.
- Manage the development of several critical web applications, used for operations reporting & intervention.
- Lead speaker in the first ever Tableau retail user group.

Senior Insight Analyst - Availability @ **Tesco PLC** 2017-2020

- Lead insight projects which shape how Tesco measures, monitors and reports availability across UK and Ireland.
 - Define the most important products for our customers, enabling endto-end focus encompassing suppliers, distribution and store operations.
 - Set availability targets for stores, groups and Company, report and review performance against the targets and highlight the underlying drivers of availability.
- Lead the international KPI alignment coordinating the Insight and Technology functions.
- Agile delivery of interactive dashboards, work with supply chain operation leads to gather requirements and develop dashboards which simplify and support operations.
 - Developed the most viewed Tableau dashboard within Tesco (Over 100,000 user views).
 - Act as subject expert mentoring the insight team on dashboard best practices and effective visualisations.
 - Developed the visualisations behind an IGD award finalist project.
- Manage work and development of one direct report.

Insight Analyst - Availability @ Tesco PLC

2015-2017

- Work alongside the lead data scientist, developing automated solutions to support decision making.
- Perform regular Ad hoc analysis to address availability issues timely and gain an understanding of performance challenges.

CONTACT

Email:

Michail Karnas@hotmail.com

Phone: +44 7519273839

Address: Al7 1FX, Welwyn Garden

City, Hertfordshire

EDUCATION

MSc Operations and Logistics Management

University of Surrey 2014 - 2015

Meng in Civil Engineering

National Technical University of Athens 2007 - 2013

SKILLS

Tableau

Teradata SOL

Excel & VBA

SOL Server

SSIS

Hadoop

Pyspark

Oozie

Interests

E-Sports

Poker

Programming

Cinema